视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
百年乡情
第二季  第一集
翻译：windy  krystal  jophy  ruben  espionage
校对：Brian  慕斯  小P
后期：D     时间轴：阿黎     总监：慕斯
哦 它没呼吸了 快点
Ah, it's not breathing. Come on!
稻草
Straw.
清干净了
It's clear.
继续啊
Keep trying!
快点 快点
Come on, come on...
真棒
Yes!
看到没
See!
新生命
New life.
儿子 把牛奶拿到马车上
Get milk on cart, son.
否则我们会错过六点的火车
Or we'll miss six o'clock train.
每天都如此 从不间断
'Every day without fail,
必须赶上六点的火车
'the six o'clock train had to be caught.'
错过火车 牛奶场就会
'Miss the train and the dairy
与我们断绝联系  农场就会破产
would drop us and the farm would go under.
我们就完了
'We'd be finished.'
走
Go.
继续 莫利
Go on, Molly!
再快点
'Faster!'
再快点 快
Go faster, come on!
距离战争结束已经五年了
'For five years, since the end of the war,
我这一代人一直回视着
'my generation had been looking over their shoulders
虽然已经去世但永远年轻的哥哥们的灵魂
'at the ghosts of older brothers who would always be young.'
但前方一直在召唤我
'But up ahead calling me on
我的生活只求生存
'there was my own life begging to be lived.'
你身上都是泥巴
You're very... muddy.
有的时候
Sometimes...
我听说过他 伯特
I hear him, Bert.
并且我以为他没死
And I think he's not dead.
这很愚蠢吗
Is that foolish?
我可爱的男孩
My lovely boy.
他说 创造一个更好的世界
"Make a better world," He said.
有些人有贵人保护
Some people have saints for protection.
我会带着乔的照片的
I'll take Joe.
小心点
Be careful.
上帝和你同在 伯特 米德尔顿
God go with you, Bert Middleton.
继续 小伙子
Go on, lad!
你那叫开车吗
You call that driving?!
看 野兔
Look. It's the hare!
从没有人完成它 伯特 那我将会是第一个 没错
No-one's ever done it, Bert. I'll be the first, then. Right!
猎犬在这里 先生
The hounds are here, sir.
感谢你的到来
Thanks for coming.
我想你会好好享受这一天的
I think you'll enjoy the day.
阿林汉姆大人
Lord Allingham.
这个屋子的每个参观者名字都在这上 无一例外
Every visitor to this house is in here, without exception.
我父亲坚持这样做
My father insisted.
这是历史 他说
"It's history," He said.
他死的时候 他住在三间屋子里
When he died, he was living in three rooms.
我向他保证过我给这里重新带来欢乐
I promised him I'd make it happy again.
我们坚持做下去
We carry on.
他让仆人感到害怕
He frightens the servants.
他让首相都感到害怕 他拥有半条佛里特街
He frightens the Prime Minister. He owns half of Fleet Street
他是政党中的暗中操控者 母亲
and he's the fixer in the party, mother.
取悦他
Make him happy.
你让我听起来像个妓女
You make me sound like a common prostitute.
只是尽可能做到最好
Just do what you do best.
怎么做 尽地主之仪
And what's that? Host.
不要相信一个睡在身上毛
Never trust a man who sleeps with
比灰狗还多的东西旁的男人 波莉
anything hairier than a greyhound, Polly.
早上好 吉尔马丁 早上好 阿林汉姆夫人
Good morning, Lord Kilmartin. Good morning, Lady Allingham.
你不知道我多高兴
I can't tell you how delighted I am
因为今天你的驾到
that you're here on this day, of all days.
希望如此
I wish you would.
我很高兴今天你能光临
I am delighted that you're here on this day of all days.
你真迷人
You're a fascinating woman.
你已经是人夫了 吉尔马丁大人
And you're a married man, Lord Kilmartin.
现在 最要紧的事就是
Now, the pressing question is...
你喜欢香肠吗
..How do you like your sausage?
嗯
Hmm...
请
Please.
我给你表演一下舞步
I'll show you the steps.
乔治
George.
早餐之前来段舞 噢 棒极了
Dancing before breakfast? My, my!
来和你的妻子跳支舞吧
Come and dance with your wife!
我可以请你跳舞吗
May I have this dance?
一周前 我看见一个小男孩
A week ago, I saw a small boy
把他的手指放进电灯插座里
put his finger in an electric light socket.
电击把他抛起穿过屋子
The shock threw him clean across the room.
当他起身时 他惊声尖笑
When he got up, he was screaming with laughter.
电流 爱因斯坦 爵士乐 任何事都有可能 所以
Electricity, Einstein, jazz - anything is possible. So?
这是这个国家有史以来最重要的选举
This is the most important election this country has ever had.
吉尔马丁在这是因为他认定你
Lord Kilmartin's here because he wants YOU!
你今天表现的好  那你将是下一届的内政大臣
You play it right today, you'll be the next Home Secretary.
大家日安
Happy day.
已经十五年了 很多次我都认为
It's been 15 years and there have been times
这再也不会发生
when I thought this would never happen again.
所以 上帝保佑你们
So, God bless you all.
为了今天新来的客人  一个非常温暖的阿林汉姆式的欢迎
For those new to this day, a very warm Allingham welcome.
有一首我们经常唱的赞美诗
Now there's a hymn that we used to sing.
赞美诗没有改变 是吧
Hymns don't change, do they?
因此 请和我一起
So, please, join in with me.
我害怕没有反对者
# I fear no foe
和你一起祝福
# With Thee at hand to bless
我没有砝码
# Ills have no weight
眼泪没有怨恨
# And tears no bitterness
死亡刺痛哪儿
# Where is death's sting?
哪儿 墓穴 你的胜利
# Where, grave, thy victory?
我还是成功了
# I triumph still
你与我同在
#If Thou abide with me.
躲藏者
The runner.
围巾
Handkerchief?
我们需要这上面的气味
We'll need the scent.
把衬衫脱了
Shirt. Take it off.
味无芬芳的英格兰
England un-perfumed.
深呼吸 中世纪
Breathe deeply - the Middle Ages.
牛蒡 大麦
Burdock, barley,
猪鼻子 狗舌头 可能是吗
nose of pig's breath, dog's tongue, perhaps?
哦 是的
And... Oh, yes...
古老的乡下人的苦味
Ancient peasant bitterness.
它是我兄弟的衬衣
It was my brothers' shirt.
他死了 他去世了
He's dead. He died.
从外观来看 看来你是经常穿着的了
Whilst wearing it, by the looks.
规则如下 开始后你有十分钟的时间
The rules - you have a ten minute start.
当喇叭一吹响 我们就开始追逐
The horn blows when we begin the chase.
你必须待在阿林汉姆地界上
You must stay on Allingham
或待在村庄的边界范围内
land or within the boundaries of the village
你不能进任何屋子 明白吗
and you must not step inside any house, you understand?
如果你活下来并且没被抓住的话
If you survive and you're still free
当喇叭在一点钟再次吹响时 你就赢了  多少钱
when the horn blows again at one o'clock you win. How much?
一磅
A pound.
如果你在一点差三分时候 被吉尔马丁大人抓住的话
And if you allow yourself to be caught by Lord Kilmartin
那么在晨练后
at three minutes to one, after a good morning's sport,
我还是会给你一磅 为什么
I'll still give you a pound. Why?
你不会懂的
You wouldn't understand.
再加点赌注
Up the stakes.
他会付你两磅如果你能存活到早晨
He'll pay you two pounds if you survive the morning.
你觉得呢 阿林汉姆 够刺激才是王道
Won't you, Allingham? Incentive is everything.
当然 但是 如果他被抓住了 在余下的时间里
Of course. But, if he's caught, he'll do everything I ask of him
他将听命于我
for the rest of the day.
五磅 伯特
Five pounds. Bert...
你将是我的
You'll be mine.
我不能呆在这
I can't stay here.
我喜欢这氛围
I like it here.
走
Go.
跑呀 伯特
Run, Bert!
现在
Now!
朝着溪流
Towards the stream!
多少钱
How much?
在谢菲尔德有份摄影助理的工作
There's a job in Sheffield, for a photography assistant.
如果我今天赢了 我就够去租个房了
And, if I win today, it's enough to set me up wi' lodgings
如果他们抓住你怎么办 伯特
and everything. What if they catch you? Bert?
你不会让他们得逞的
You won't let 'em.
闻起来很糟糕
This smells terrible.
走 走
Go. Go!
他在哪
Where is he?
找到他 伙计们
Find him, boy!
新出生的小牛 一小时之前
New calf - hour ago.
你应该想到的
You should have thought of that.
再给我一周时间
Give me another week.
有点担当吧 米德尔顿
Responsibility, Middleton.
我租给了你牛棚
I rented you the cowshed,
都说好了每月三英镑的租金
we agreed the three pounds monthly rent.
可你没交 所以我要收回了
You haven't paid it, so I'm taking it back.
如果小牛死了 那是你的错 不是我的
Your fault if the calf dies, not mine.
请你现在把你的动物弄出我的牛棚
Get your animals out of my cowshed now, please.
这不是他
It's not him.
他在哪儿 他在哪儿
Where is he? WHERE IS HE?
快走 快走快走快走快走
Go! Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go...
快走 接着走 走啊
Go on. Walk on. Go on.
我爱你
I love you.
快点儿
Faster!
快 快点儿啊
Faster! Faster!
到这下面来
Get down here.
喂 你 起来
Oi, you, get up!
他在哪儿啊
Where is he?
你又是谁
Who the hell are you?
-你为什么这么做 -闭嘴 我问你个问题
-What did you do that for? -Shut up! I asked you a question!
你是聋子吗 孩子
Are you deaf, boy?
抱歉 说错了 黑鬼
Sorry, wrong word. Nigger.
再说一遍
Say that again.
回答他
Answer him!
嘿
Hey!
在上面 看啊 他在哪儿 是他
Up there, look! There he is! It's him!
快来
Come on.
感觉就像你向我求婚的时候
It feels like when you proposed to me.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
风把你的帽子吹掉了 就在你正要
Wind blew your cap off just as you were about to...
他把牛棚收回了 小拉特
He's taking cowshed back, young Rutter.
-他比他的父亲要混蛋多了 -为什么
-He's twice the bastard his father ever was. -Why?
我们欠他租金
We owe him rent.
-嗯 我们去哪儿挤奶呢 -在田野里
-Well, where we going to do the milking? -In field.
什么 一天两次吗  在冬天吗 约翰
What, twice a day?! In winter, John?!
嗯 我们只是要早起一点 晚睡一点
Well, we'll just have to get up earlier and go to bed later.
然后用上帝给的每个小时工作
And work every hour that God sends.
八年来你每天都祈祷 他到底要什么
You have prayed every day for eight years. What does he want?
你一无所得却还要继续付出
How much more are you going to give him for nothing in return?!
事情一定会改变的
Something's got to change,
约翰 要这么做的是我们
John, and it's us that've got to do it.
小牛会死吗
Is the calf going to die?
咱们把她带到田野里吧
Let's get her up into field.
她最好和她妈妈在一起
Her best chance is to be with her mother,
喝到前十二小时的初乳以免得病
get first 12 hours of milk to protect her from diseases.
之后 如果她活下来了 我们可以在屋里用奶瓶喂她
And then, if she survives, we might bottle-feed her inside.
父亲不会让她死的
Father won't let her die.
你捡起来了 我的帽子
You picked it up - my cap.
你把帽子给我戴上
You put it back on my head...
然后你说 是的
and then you said yes.
我也爱你
I love you too.
他在那儿
There he is!
快来
Come on!
我们就要抓到他了
We're on him.
-噢 先生 抱歉 -让开 该死的
-Oh! Sorry, sir. -Out of my way, damn you!
你跑不了了
Got ya!
他也许能做到
He might do it.
130年了 野兔从来没有幸存过
130 years and a hare has never survived.
他在哪儿 他在哪儿
Where is he? Where is he!?
你应该停下来在浴室洗个澡的 伯特
You should have stopped for a wash in bath house, Bert.
嗯 记得透过屋顶偷看的时光吗 那是我们多大
Eh, remember that time looking through roof? How old were we?
12岁半
12 and a half.
-你在看什么 -谁也没看 你在看谁 伯特
-Who were you looking at? -Nobody. Who were you looking at, Bert?
那是过去的事了 不是吗
That's the thing about the past, isn't it?
每次你看的时候 都会有更多的
Every time you look, there's more of it.
深刻 他真是思想深刻
So profound. He's so profound.
你知道的 你可以做老师的
You know, you could be a teacher.
你最怀念童年的什么
What do you miss most about childhood?
歌声 曾经有更多的歌声
Singing. There were more singing.
母亲曾经用啤酒给我们洗头 我和乔伊
My mother used to wash our hair in beer - me and Joe.
他会很为你骄傲的
He'd have been proud of you.
#我拿着钞票去了市场
# As I was going to Darby Upon a market day
#我看到了最大的公羊呀 是用干草喂的
# I saw the biggest ram, sir That ever was fed on hay
#是个谎言 是个谎言 是个谎言
#It's a lie, it's a lie It's a lie, a lie,
你赢了吗
Did you win?
不 他作弊了
No. He cheated!
作弊了
Cheated?
进入了一个村妇的前室 违反了所有规定
Went into a village woman's front room, against all the rules.
嗯 那很好 那么 追猎者又赢了
Well, that's good, then. The hounds win again.
-午饭吃什么 -鲑鱼
-What's for lunch? -Trout.
伯特作弊了吗
Bert cheated?
你听到那个人怎么说了 玛莎
You heard what the man said, Martha.
欺骗 谎言 女士的前室
Cheating, lies, ladies' front rooms?
基尔马丁有这全部三种的天赋
Kilmartin has a talent for all three! I'm sorry?
当基尔马丁向他女儿求婚时
Lord Chater was concerned when Kilmartin
蔡特勋爵很担心
asked for his daughter's hand,
以为基尔马丁是为了政治目的这么做的
that he was after political advancement.
他错了 他是瞄准了他的整个家庭
He was wrong. He was after his whole family!
到底是哪个家庭成员
Which member of the family was he actually...
他事实上上了他的妻子 妻子的表妹
He's actually fucking his wife, his wife's cousin
和他继子的妻子
and his stepdaughter-in-law!
蔡特勋爵不知道
Chater doesn't know.
他到底是什么样的人
What kind of a man is he?
半天 阿林厄姆 一个下午
Half a day, Allingham, one afternoon.
让他保持微笑 你的职业生涯就会腾飞
Keep him smiling and your career is launched.
抓住她 抓住她
Hold. Hold her, hold her.
还有件事 阿尔伯特 爱因斯坦
And another thing, Albert Einstein.
谁
Who?
不再是以前的那个时代了
Time is not what it used to be.
这不是我们能用来衡量一切的常数
It's not a constant against which we can all measure everything.
它是相对的
It is relative.
所以我们只能靠自己 我们每个人
So we're on our own, all of us.
你要说什么 他在说些什么
What are you on about? What's he on about?
他说重要的是要留下自己的印记
He's saying it's important to leave your mark.
你去哪了
Where were you?
我赢了五英镑
I've won five pounds.
妈妈
Mother!
-你拿到了么 -承诺给我了
-Have you got it? -Promised me.
告诉她
Tell her.
我赢了五英镑
I've won five pounds.
是他的钱
It's his money.
是你的钱 伯特
It's your money, Bert.
我们欠拉特多少钱
How much do we owe Rutter?
三英镑
Three pounds.
不 太晚了
No, it's too late.
-租期什么时候到期 -今天
-When's rent due? -Today.
嗯 今天还没结束 对吧
Well, today's not over, is it?
脱下夹克
Jacket off.
民有的男人不会觉得冷
A man of the people doesn't feel the cold.
国会开幕典礼 国王的演讲
The State Opening of Parliament, the King's Speech,
圣诞早晨 我自己的生日
Christmas morning, my own birthday,
我愿意放弃掉所有这些以换取我们村子这一特殊的日子
I'd give them all up for this special day in our village.
-300来 一位阿林汉姆 -他让我想起我父亲
-For 300 years, an Allingham... -He reminds me of my father.
站在了我站的地方
..Has stood where I now
让这个美好的传统继续流传
stand and kept this wonderful tradition alive.
我们一度远离这里 我们都是 我们一度被考验
We've been away for a while, we all have, and we've been tested,
但我们通过了考验 而今天 今天标志着
but we have come through and today, today marks the return of
我们为之奋战的英式生活的回归
that English way of life we've all been fighting for.
谢谢 享受着一天  祝好
Thank you. Enjoy the day. Box well.
感谢你们来 谢谢 很高兴见到你们
Thank you for coming along. Thank you. Lovely to see you.
我叫比利吉比
My name's Bill Gibby.
我想问两个问题
And I want to ask two questions:
我是谁 你是谁
Who am I? Who are you?
试着把两个问题都回答了
And try to answer them both.
在这里我是局外人 但我知道这个国家
I'm an outsider here. But I know this country.
肺脏 我们市民是这么称呼这个地方的
"The lung" Us townsfolk call the place
你们很幸运地把这个地方叫做家
you're fortunate enough to call home.
我曾每周日来这儿
And I used to come up here every Sunday.
我是为了这里的空气来的
It was my coming up for air,
我花了6年挖矿
for the six years I spent mining coal.
之后我又花了4年
Then I had another four years
在德国的线路下挖土设置爆炸物
digging under the German lines to set explosives.
这种生活艰难吗 也许
Has it been a tough life? Maybe.
我觉得我自己悲惨吗 一点也不
Do I feel sorry for meself? Not a bit of it.
因为我知道一件事
Cos if there's one thing I know,
我们不会获得真正的自由
it's that none of us will be free
除非我们自己
until we stop thinking of
不再视自己为受害者
ourselves as victims and become masters...
-和情人 -并成为自己生命和未来的主人
- and mistresses - of our own lives and our own futures.
这有一首诗
Here's a poem.
英国人 荣誉的传人
Men of England, heirs of Glory
未来故事里的英雄
Heroes of unwritten story
伟大母亲的后裔
Nurslings of one mighty Mother
她的希望 互为希冀
Hopes of her, and one another
像雄狮一般苏醒崛起
Rise like Lions after slumber
不可征服的一群勇士
In unvanquishable number
像抖掉露珠般
Shake your chains to earth like dew
抖落你沉睡时被套上的枷锁
Which in sleep had fallen on you -
你们千万人 他们一小撮
Ye are many - they are few.
雪莉能为我解答
Shelley has the answer to my questions.
我是谁 你是谁
Who am I? Who are you?
我们是一体的
We are one!
团结一致 我们便所向无敌
And together, we are unvanquishable!
说得好 先生 干得漂亮
Well said, sir. Very well done.
来自暗黑大陆的丛林最深处
Here from the deepest jungle of the darkest continent
为你挑选最佳勇士
for you to pit your best men against.
谁有勇气来接受挑战
Who has the courage to take on
萨维奇 阿菲利加
Savage Africa?
153场比赛的不败神话
153 fights undefeated.
谁会是第一个击败萨维奇 阿菲利加的人呢
Who will be the first man to beat Savage Africa?
上 去赢走你的钱
Go and get your money.
谁会是第一个
Who's first?
能打上一回合 赢得 一英镑
Survive a round and win... A pound!
我们的第一位挑战者   站起来吧
Our first contender, step right up.
大家掌声鼓励
Give him a round of applause, everyone.
你作弊
You cheated.
抱歉
Sorry.
伯特
Bert?
他们说我作弊
They said I cheated.
-但你没有  -当然没有
-But you didn't. -No!
所以
So?
一边基尔马丁勋爵 艾德蒙 阿林汉姆  一边是我和你 算了吧
Lord Kilmartin, Edmund Allingham, me and you? Forget it!
在军队里我可是拳击冠军
I was boxing champ in the army, you know.
我要你帮我做点事
There's something I want you to do for me.
多少？
How much?
一 二 三 四 五
One, two, three, four, five,
六 七 八 九
six, seven, eight, nine,
十 比赛结束
ten. It's over.
如果把牛犊留在田里一整夜的话
Our calf will die of cold
牛犊会被冻死的
if she's left out in the field all night.
我知道你不喜欢我丈夫 或者我们全家
I... I know you don't like my husband, or our family,
但是 求求你 今晚让我们用一下牛棚好吗
but PLEASE can we have the cowshed tonight?
如果我给你加时的话，下星期又会是怎样
If I give you extra time, what will it be next week?
你不能一直这样
You can't go on like this.
我想这也是你会在这里的原因
I think that's why you're here.
小牛需要温暖
The calf needs warmth.
我也需要
So do I.
-抱歉 我听不懂  -不 你懂的
-Sorry, but I don't understand... -Yes, you do.
为什么不是你的丈夫来找我
Why didn't your husband
如果你没有这个意思的话
come to see me if it weren't on your mind?
这是一个邀请
It's an offer.
上个星期六我在博尔索佛见过他
I saw him last Saturday up at Bolsover Colliery.
15名矿工一个接着一个上 他把他们都击倒了
15 miners one after the other and he put them all down.
下一个是谁
Who is next?
打赢一回合并赢得一英镑
Survive a round and win a pound!
英格兰人 是狮子还是羔羊
Men of England, are you lions or lambs?
好吧 两英镑
All right, two pounds!
还是没人
Still nobody.
我从未给过这么样的奖品         3英镑
Here's an offer I've never made before, three pounds!
上来吧 他们全都试着打赢他
Step right up. They're all trying to fight him.
你不需要打赢他   你只要撑上一回合
You don't need to fight him, you just need to survive.
约翰  不要鼓励他
John?! Don't encourage him.
我们需要那钱
We need the money.
来吧 先生
Come on, gentlemen!
动起来 就像我教你的那样
Move your feet, like I taught you.
加油 儿子 打倒他
Move, son! Knock him down!
就是这样
That's it.
加油   打他
Come on! Hit him!
动起来 伯特
Move, Bert!
我不想打死你 躺下来
I don't want to kill ya. Go down.
一  二    三
One, two, three...
站起来      四
Come on! ..Four...
五    六
..Five, six...
七
..Seven...
八
..Eight...
你还好吗 儿子   要继续吗
You all right, son? Do you want to go on?
没事吧       他没事   他没事
You all right? He's all right, he's all right.
继续 伯特 加油 打他
Keep moving, Bert. Come on! Hit him!
击倒
Knock out.
胜利者
Winner!
你他妈的在打什么啊
What the fuck are you playing at, eh?
你儿子  是的
Your boy? Yes.
-他叫什么名字  -伯特 米德尔顿
-What's his name? -Bert Middleton.
是那个王八蛋吗
It's that bastard.
-他会打败你  -不 他不会
-He'll knock you down. -No, he won't.
不 他会
Yes, he will.
谁说的
Who says?
不 他违规了
No! That was below the belt.
一  二
One, two...
三   四
three, four...
五     六
five, six...
七  八
seven, eight...
站起来
Come on!
九    躺下去  躺下去
nine... Stay down! Stay down!
结束了 孩子 待在这  比赛结束了
It's over, son. Stay there. It's over.
胜利者
The winner!
我从没输过
Well, I never.
基尔马丁宝刀未老
Good old Kilmartin.
恭喜你  太了不起了
Congratulations. Fantastic.
20英镑 为了你的败北
20 pounds, for you to lose.
但 天啊 你不能败倒在这20英镑之下
But, oh no, you can't fall over for 20 pounds.
我不会放弃任何一场比赛
I won't throw a fight.
这不是拳击
This is not boxing.
这是娱乐业  而我是制片人
This is showbusiness and I'm the producer.
我不要你的臭钱
I don't want your dirty money.
我也不需要你
And I don't need you.
真的吗 好
Really? Fine.
把我的东西还给我然后滚蛋
Give me what's mine and go.
手套 短裤 靴子
Gloves, shorts, boots.
走啊 你可以走了
Go on, then. Off you go.
进来
Come in.
你没有妻子的 艾德蒙
You've no wife, Edmund.
关于基尔马丁勋爵我们知道些什么
So, what do we know about Lord Kilmartin?
他是个土霸王
He's a bully
是个骗子
and a cheat
还有 他是你最好的朋友
and he's your best friend.
他会安排我进内阁
He'll put me in the Cabinet.
重要的是得到了权利
It's what you do when you're
过程并不重要
in power that matters, not how you get there.
这得看你为了权利伤害了谁
That depends on who you hurt getting there.
还有你的良心
And your conscience.
重音应该放在 鸡 上面还是 酒 上面
Does one put the stress on "Cock" Or "Tail"?
是鸡 尾酒 还是鸡尾 酒 呢？
Is it cockTAIL or COCKtail?
不管怎样
Anyway...
嗯
Mm...
天啊 真是好喝得吓人啊
Oh, this is... appalling
艾德温娜 蒙巴顿
Edwina Mountbatten.
绝对的性欲狂
Absolute maniac for sex.
千万别和艾德温娜搭同一辆车  哦
Do not get in a taxi with Edwina. Oh?
我离开一下 阿林汉姆夫人
Will you excuse me a moment, Lady Allingham?
她对你好吗
Was she nice to you?
我发现芳香的衰落是如此的醉人
I find fragrant decay so moving.
她就像夏日最有一朵三色堇花
She's like the last pansy of summer.
你为什么倒下了
Why didn't you go down?
因为我傻
Stupid.
是勇敢
Brave.
两者都有吧
Maybe both.
像战场上的英国兵那样
Like Tommies in the war.
你是不是
Did you...
那是为了什么
What was it for?
我为了我的国家而战
I fought for me country,
但在那之后他们不让我继续打拳击赛
but they won't let me fight for boxing titles after it.
为什么
Why?
因为我的肤色
Because of the colour of me skin.
至少我熬过来了
At least I got through it, eh?
那是乔
That's our Joe.
黎明时被射死
Shot at dawn.
就发生在我最好朋友身上
It happened to me best friend.
他们派了个人拿着瓶威士忌
They send a man in, after the priest,
跟在神父之后进来
with a bottle of whisky.
就算为了让他醉倒
The idea is to get him so drunk that
让他死的时候毫无所觉
when dawn comes he hardly knows what's happening to him.
那晚我整晚陪在他身边
I stayed with him all night.
但他不怕 也不喝酒
But he weren't afraid and he wouldn't drink.
我不想在生命的最后时刻仍意识不清
"I don't want to spend me last hours unconscious."
你当时和他在一起么
You were with him?
我半夜的时候进去了
I went in at midnight.
他说他热爱生命 现在还剩下为数不多的时间
He said that he loved life and there's some of it left,
所以我们不会把时间浪费在谈论死亡的问题上
so we won't waste it talking about death and dying.
那 那你们都谈论了些什么
What... What did you talk about?
他的家人
His family.
他想让我告诉他的家人们 虽然他在世的时间并不长
He wanted me to tell them that, although his life was short...
但是他很庆幸能和自己的家人们一起度过这段时光
..He were lucky to have shared it with them.
你那儿沾了一点泥巴
You've got a bit of mud.
这儿 不是 来 过来
Here? No, come here.
世界真是美好 妈妈
Make it a better world, mother.
我们一起抽了根烟
We were having a cigarette.
我们
"We"?
这是你的演讲
Your speech.
我觉得我应该把这些逐字写下来
I thought I should write
以免你觉得有点 呃
it word for word in case you're feeling, er,
混乱 关于那个派对和其他事情
out of joint - party and everything.
我知道在一个派对上讨论政治不合时宜
I know this is a party and no place for politics.
可是 很快将会有一场选举
However... there is an election coming.
-我们会赢得这场选举 -听 听
- Which we'll win. - Hear, hear.
你们有些人可能听了与我党对立的工党今天的言论
Some of you may have heard my Labour opponent speak today...
我可以来根香烟么
Could I have a cigarette?
我不抽烟 不好意思 从我个人来说
I don't smoke, sorry. ..Personally I
我更喜欢看一场拳击比赛
was more interested in what I saw in the boxing ring...
主要是关于决心 毅力 勇气 -伯特米德尔顿
Mainly determination, courage, pluck - Bert Middleton.
他并没有伙伴可以并肩作战 只有一个人
He wasn't in the ring with his comrades, it was him in there -
只身一人 挑战不可能
alone and against the odds.
那才是人类的精神 是我们本身应该具有的
That's human spirit, that's what we're made of.
社会主义总是鼓吹说是为了大众的利益 其实不然
Socialism pretends to be for the good of everyone. It's not.
那是人类进步的阻碍
It's a hand-brake on mankind.
只有个人的努力
It's individual endeavour
才能让这个国家成为一个
that will make this country into a nation
可以被大家称之为
about which it is still possible to say,
一个英雄的国度
"This is a land fit for heroes."
听啊听啊 那是我的儿子
Hear, hear. He's my son.
你之前说他是个骗子 现在又说他是个英雄
You said he was a cheat, now a hero.
到底是哪个呢
Which is it?
他违反了规定 去了玛格丽特博登的房子
He went into Margaret Boden's house in breach of the rules.
我说的对吗 基尔马丁大人
Am I right, Lord Kilmartin?
当然
Absolutely.
所以是你儿子的言论忤逆了王公贵族
So it's your son's word against that of a peer of the realm.
你就想把他交给基尔马丁大人
Then you'll be handing him over to Lord Kilmartin.
你是在赌你的运气
That WAS the wager.
埃德蒙
Edmund?
给她钱
Pay her.
米德尔顿
Middleton.
我从没忘记一个名字
I never forget a name.
荣誉 是一个男人最重要的东西 男人绝不能容许侮辱
Honour, a man's name, not being embarrassed in public -
每一件你和基尔马丁在意的事
everything that matters to Kilmartin and you,
你为了一个农村的孩子和他的母亲让他颜面尽失
you threw it in his face for a farm boy and his mother!
总有人得坚守原则
Someone has to be principled,
贝尔斯托 我这么做是对的
Bairstow. It was the right thing to do.
也得有人坚守过去的原则 阿林厄姆
And someone has to see past principles, Allingham!
你来这儿是为了改变我的想法 是吧
You've come to make me change my mind, I suppose?
不 我是想让阿林厄姆小姐告诉Chater大人
No, I was thinking of asking Lady Allingham to tell Lord Chater
你正在找他的家人的麻烦
which members of his family you're fucking.
你是在威胁我吗
Are you blackmailing me?
正是
Absolutely.
阿林厄姆小姐
Lady Allingham?
等一会行吗
A moment?
虚伪
Bluff!
打给我
Call me.
基尔马丁大人要你第一个听到这个消息
Lord Kilmartin wanted you to be the first to hear it.
我打算让你的儿子成为下一任内政大臣
I'm going to make your son the next Home Secretary.
嗷 我的上帝
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, my goodness!
我已经 嗯
I've, erm...
嗯 我来是为了给你一样你一直要求的东西
Well, I've come to give you what you've been asking for.
你在哪儿 去拿钱了
Where have you been? To get the money.
你拿到了吗 是的
Did you get it? Yes.
你付钱给拉特了吗 我为什么要那么做
Did you pay Rutter? Why would I do that?
它是你的了 伯特 这是你赚来的
It's yours, Bert. You've earnt it.
父亲
Father?
儿子
Son?
情况变了 我们有麻烦了
'Something had changed. We were in trouble -
牛棚没了 冬天延长了 厨房里只有一个牛犊
'no cowshed, more months of winter and a calf in the kitchen.
五磅可是一大笔钱
'Five pounds was a lot of money.
它可以支付一个散工一段时间的工资了
'It would pay for casual labour for a time,
但是这也不够
but it wouldn't be enough.
但是和我的家人一起站在那儿
'But standing there, with my family,
我们知道我们相聚在一起
'we knew we'd been brought together.
他会一直和我在一起的 -乔
'He would always be with me - Joe -
而且 像我的妈妈一样 我会一直倾听他的
'and, like my mother, I would keep hearing him...
但我已经不再回首过去
'But I'd stopped looking over my shoulder
而是开始期待着 新的生活
'and begun looking forward - to a new life.'